To influence others, consider changing how you ask questions.
Communication expert Matt Abrahams
emphasizes that asking questions can elevate your status
and demonstrate empathy, care, and a willingness to learn.
Effective leaders balance credibility with humility
and know how to ask the right questions
to strengthen relationships and advance their careers.
Good questions should be concise,
build on previous conversation points,
and focus on a specific idea.
Before asking, consider your intention,
whether to show understanding, express interest,
or guide the conversation.
Avoid asking questions just for participation points,
as they should always be thoughtful and relevant.
To practice, treat casual interactions like interviews,
aiming to learn more about the other person.
If you struggle with concise questioning,
use tools like AI to refine your phrasing.
Most importantly, listen actively before asking
as this fosters collaboration and strengthens relationships.